<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" /><updated>2021-09-04T14:04:55+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">LISEM</title><subtitle>LISEM website, open-source spatial modelling software download and tutorials.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Release of 0.1.1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/09/04/Release-0.1.1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Release of 0.1.1" /><published>2020-09-04T11:41:09+02:00</published><updated>2020-09-04T11:41:09+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/09/04/Release-0.1.1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/09/04/Release-0.1.1/">&lt;p&gt;We have seen some activity on the downloads pages on sourceforge for the new LISEM software!
Thanks for your interest!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you all have had some uses for the software. If there are any issues or questions, please contact us.
You can use the github discussions page, or email b.vandenbout@utwente.nl&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, there is a new version: 0.1.1. See the downloads page for the available files.
You will find a lot of bug fixes, stability and memory issues resolved.
Additionally, there is now reasonably good support for 3d datasets with the introduction of the Field object.
You can use similar code as for maps, except the data is stored as .fld (3d netcdf file internally).
so: a.fld = b.fld + sin(ZCoord(c.fld));
These fields can be used with the (now working) 3d water flow model (FlowIncompressible3D) and seismic model based on SW4 (SeismicModel class).
There are also major improvements to the rigid physics simulation using the Project Chrono library. These can be used from the scripting language and interact with 3d and 2d water flow.
Tutorials will be added at some point to this site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your interest and happy modelling!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bastian&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bastian van den Bout</name></author><summary type="html">We have seen some activity on the downloads pages on sourceforge for the new LISEM software! Thanks for your interest!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Alpha release of the new LISEM!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/07/09/Alpha-Release/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Alpha release of the new LISEM!" /><published>2020-07-09T11:41:09+02:00</published><updated>2020-07-09T11:41:09+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/07/09/Alpha-Release</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/07/09/Alpha-Release/">&lt;p&gt;Today we have finally uploaded a first link to the compiled new version of LISEM.
This is not just the model, but the full software with all of the tools.
Some of these are slightly (understatement) ambitious. 
Thus, a solid warning is in place:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This software is in alpha release!
There will be bugs, issues and sometimes confusing elements to the interface and algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will proceed during the summer and fall to fix the majority of the remaining bugs.
For now, if you wish to use it, check out the docs pages on this website.
If you have comments, found a bug thats particularly nasty, or want to contribute, 
please check the about page for details on how to contact us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for your interest!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bastian&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bastian van den Bout</name></author><summary type="html">Today we have finally uploaded a first link to the compiled new version of LISEM. This is not just the model, but the full software with all of the tools. Some of these are slightly (understatement) ambitious. Thus, a solid warning is in place:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The new LISEM website is under development!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/10/Under-Development/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The new LISEM website is under development!" /><published>2020-05-10T11:41:09+02:00</published><updated>2020-05-10T11:41:09+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/10/Under-Development</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/10/Under-Development/">&lt;p&gt;Thank you for checking out the LISEM project.
We are currently reworking the website and project code.
Please come back at a later moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-c&quot; data-lang=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;while&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;modeller&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Check_Website&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;std&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;current_time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;());&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name>Bastian van den Bout</name></author><summary type="html">Thank you for checking out the LISEM project. We are currently reworking the website and project code. Please come back at a later moment.</summary></entry></feed>